Archives and Records Management Department fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Archives and Records Management Department fonds
1963 - 1999
F-51
1.75 m of textual records 244 photographs: negative prints 26 photographs: contact sheets
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
PHYSICAL DESCRIPTION: 244 photographs (negative prints)/26 photographs (contact sheets) located in F-51-7-0-0-1, F-51-7-0-0-2, F-51-7-0-0-3
Archives and Records Management Department
The University Archives acquires, preserves and makes available three categories of materials: (1) the official records of the University, including those created by the Board of Governors, Senate, University committees, faculties, departments and administrative offices; (2) materials documenting the wider University community; and (3) historical research collections that promote the teaching and research activities of the University.
The Archives was established within the University Library in 1968 when librarian Liisa Fagerlund was appointed University Archivist on a half-time basis. She continued in this post until 1975 when she left the University. From 1975 to 1978, the Archives functioned within the Special Collections division of the Library. Archival duties were carried out by various library staff members. In 1978, the University Archives was established as a separate administrative unit outside of the Library. Donald Baird, recently retired as University Librarian, became University Archivist and held this position until his retirement in 1990. Jim Ross served as University Archivist from 1991 to 1993, and was succeeded by Ian Forsyth in 1994.
When the Archives was a function of the University Library, the University Archivist reported to the University Librarian. When the Archives was established as a separate administrative unit, the University Archivist reported directly to the University President. The reporting structure changed in 1986 when the University Archivist reported to the Vice-President, Research/Information Systems; in 1990, when the University Archivist reported to the Associate Vice-President, Academic; and in 1996, when the University Archivist reported to the Registrar/Dean of Students.
published
Full
Revised
Title based on provenance.
The fonds consists of records arising from the activities of the University Archives. Fonds includes correspondence, memoranda, reports, classification and description records, Archives and Records Management Advisory Committee records, and materials arising from special projects and conferences.
Don Baird; Photographic materials; Textual records
Additional material has been accessioned but not yet processed (as of September 2002: 67 cm., 1992-1995). Please consult the archivist for information about using these materials; restrictions may apply. Further accruals are expected.
Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as required by law. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
Series descriptions, subseries descriptions, and file lists are available.
- University Archivist, 1963 - 1991; F-51-1; 1.11 m of textual records
  published
  Series consists of records arising from the work of the University Archivist. Series includes correspondence, memoranda, and monthly reports.
  Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as required by law. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
  - Correspondence and memoranda, 1968 - 1991; F-51-1-1; 1.06 m of textual records
    Subseries consists of correspondence and memoranda of the University Archivist. Subseries includes letters and memoranda received, and copies of letters and memoranda sent. Correspondents include the University President, other University officers, external organizations and individuals, and members of the archival community. Subseries also includes some accompanying reports.
    - Correspondence, 1963 - 1971; F-51-1-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 51-1)
      Textual records
      Pending review
    - Correspondence, 1968 - 1986; F-51-1-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 51-1)
    - Correspondence, 1969 - 1973; F-51-1-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 51-1)
    - Correspondence, 1970 - 1974; F-51-1-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 51-1)
    - Correspondence, 1975; F-51-1-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 51-1)
    - Correspondence, 1976; F-51-1-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 51-1)
    - Correspondence, 1977; F-51-1-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 51-1)
    - Correspondence, 1978; F-51-1-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 51-1)
    - Correspondence, 1978; F-51-1-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 51-1)
    - Correspondence, 1979; F-51-1-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 51-1)
    - Correspondence, 1979; F-51-1-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 51-2)
    - Correspondence, 1980; F-51-1-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 51-2)
    - Correspondence, 1980; F-51-1-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 51-2)
    - Correspondence, 1980; F-51-1-1-0-14 (Archival box - standard 51-2)
    - Correspondence, 1981; F-51-1-1-0-15 (Archival box - standard 51-2)
    - Correspondence, 1981; F-51-1-1-0-16 (Archival box - standard 51-2)
    - Correspondence, 1981; F-51-1-1-0-17 (Archival box - standard 51-2)
    - Correspondence, 1982; F-51-1-1-0-18 (Archival box - standard 51-3)
    - Correspondence, 1982; F-51-1-1-0-19 (Archival box - standard 51-3)
    - Correspondence, 1982; F-51-1-1-0-20 (Archival box - standard 51-3)
    - Correspondence, 1982; F-51-1-1-0-21 (Archival box - standard 51-3)
    - Correspondence, 1983; F-51-1-1-0-22 (Archival box - standard 51-3)
    - Correspondence, 1983; F-51-1-1-0-23 (Archival box - standard 51-3)
    - Correspondence, 1983; F-51-1-1-0-24 (Archival box - standard 51-3)
    - Correspondence, 1983; F-51-1-1-0-25 (Archival box - standard 51-3)
    - Correspondence, 1984; F-51-1-1-0-26 (Archival box - standard 51-3)
    - Correspondence, 1984; F-51-1-1-0-27 (Archival box - standard 51-3)
    - Correspondence, 1985; F-51-1-1-0-28 (Archival box - standard 51-4)
    - Correspondence, 1985; F-51-1-1-0-29 (Archival box - standard 51-4)
    - Correspondence, 1985 - 1990; F-51-1-1-0-30 (Archival box - standard 51-4)
    - Correspondence, 1986; F-51-1-1-0-31 (Archival box - standard 51-4)
    - Correspondence, 1986; F-51-1-1-0-32 (Archival box - standard 51-4)
    - Correspondence, 1987; F-51-1-1-0-33 (Archival box - standard 51-4)
    - Correspondence, 1987; F-51-1-1-0-34 (Archival box - standard 51-4)
    - Correspondence, 1988; F-51-1-1-0-35 (Archival box - standard 51-5)
    - Correspondence, 1988; F-51-1-1-0-36 (Archival box - standard 51-5)
    - Correspondence, 1989; F-51-1-1-0-37 (Archival box - standard 51-5)
    - Correspondence, 1989; F-51-1-1-0-38 (Archival box - standard 51-5)
    - Correspondence, 1990; F-51-1-1-0-39 (Archival box - standard 51-5)
    - Correspondence, 1990; F-51-1-1-0-40 (Archival box - standard 51-5)
    - Correspondence, 1991; F-51-1-1-0-41 (Archival box - standard 51-6)
    - Correspondence, 1991; F-51-1-1-0-42 (Archival box - standard 51-6)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1974; F-51-1-1-0-43 (Archival box - standard 51-6)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1975; F-51-1-1-0-44 (Archival box - standard 51-6)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1976; F-51-1-1-0-45 (Archival box - standard 51-6)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1977; F-51-1-1-0-46 (Archival box - standard 51-6)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1978; F-51-1-1-0-47 (Archival box - standard 51-6)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1979; F-51-1-1-0-48 (Archival box - standard 51-6)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1980; F-51-1-1-0-49 (Archival box - standard 51-6)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1981; F-51-1-1-0-50 (Archival box - standard 51-6)
    - Memoranda, 1982; F-51-1-1-0-51 (Archival box - standard 51-6)
    - Memoranda, 1983; F-51-1-1-0-52 (Archival box - standard 51-6)
    - Memoranda, 1984; F-51-1-1-0-53 (Archival box - standard 51-7)
    - Memoranda, 1985; F-51-1-1-0-54 (Archival box - standard 51-7)
    - Memoranda, 1985; F-51-1-1-0-55 (Archival box - standard 51-7)
    - Memoranda, 1986; F-51-1-1-0-56 (Archival box - standard 51-7)
    - Memoranda, 1986; F-51-1-1-0-57 (Archival box - standard 51-7)
    - Memoranda, 1987; F-51-1-1-0-58 (Archival box - standard 51-7)
    - Memoranda, 1987; F-51-1-1-0-59 (Archival box - standard 51-7)
    - Memoranda, 1988; F-51-1-1-0-60 (Archival box - standard 51-7)
    - Memoranda, 1988; F-51-1-1-0-61 (Archival box - standard 51-7)
    - Memoranda, 1989; F-51-1-1-0-62 (Archival box - standard 51-7)
    - Memoranda, 1989; F-51-1-1-0-63 (Archival box - standard 51-8)
    - Memoranda, 1990; F-51-1-1-0-64 (Archival box - standard 51-8)
    - Memoranda, 1990; F-51-1-1-0-65 (Archival box - standard 51-8)
    - Memoranda, 1991; F-51-1-1-0-66 (Archival box - standard 51-8)
    - Memoranda, 1991; F-51-1-1-0-67 (Archival box - standard 51-8)
    - Correspondence with President, 1978 - 1979; F-51-1-1-0-68 (Archival box - standard 51-9)
    - Correspondence with President, 1980; F-51-1-1-0-69 (Archival box - standard 51-9)
    - Correspondence with President, 1981; F-51-1-1-0-70 (Archival box - standard 51-9)
    - Correspondence with President, 1982; F-51-1-1-0-71 (Archival box - standard 51-9)
    - Correspondence with President, 1983; F-51-1-1-0-72 (Archival box - standard 51-9)
    - Correspondence with President, 1984; F-51-1-1-0-73 (Archival box - standard 51-9)
  - Reports, 1970 - 1983; F-51-1-2; 5 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of reports compiled by the University Archivist. Reports include information summarizing the activities of the University Archives. Most reports are monthly. The individuals to whom the reports are directed change according to the place of the Archives within the organizational structure of the university. For instance, when the Archives was a function of the University Library, all reports were directed to the University Librarian.
    - Monthly Reports, 1970 - 1976; F-51-1-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 51-9)
    - Monthly Reports, 1978 - 1979; F-51-1-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 51-9)
    - Monthly Reports (includes some memoranda), 1980 - 1981; F-51-1-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 51-9)
    - Monthly Reports, 1982 - 1983; F-51-1-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 51-9)
- Administration, 1987 - 1993; F-51-2; 13 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records arising from the general administration of the University Archives.
  - General staff meetings, 1993; F-51-2-1; 2 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of records arising from general meetings of Archives staff members. Sub-series includes agendas and draft minutes. Materials relate to staff activities, Archives policy formulation, and other matters.
    - General staff meetings, 1993; F-51-2-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 51-10)
  - Advisory Committee for Archives and Records Management, 1987 - 1993; F-51-2-2; 11 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of records of the Advisory committee for archives and records management. Subseries includes meeting agendas and minutes, memoranda, reports, and other materials. Materials relate to archival policies, procedures, and practices; records management policies; Freedom of Information/Protection of Privacy issues; and other matters.
    - Advisory Committee for Archives and Records Management, 1987; F-51-2-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 51-10)
    - Advisory Committee for Archives and Records Management, 1988; F-51-2-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 51-10)
    - Advisory Committee for Archives and Records Management, 1989; F-51-2-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 51-10)
    - Advisory Committee for Archives and Records Management, 1990; F-51-2-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 51-10)
    - Advisory Committee for Archives and Records Management, 1991; F-51-2-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 51-10)
    - Advisory Committee for Archives and Records Management, 1992; F-51-2-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 51-10)
    - Advisory Committee for Archives and Records Management, 1993; F-51-2-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 51-10)
- Municipal records deaccession, 1965 - 1999; F-51-3; 13 cm of textual records
  When the University Archives was established, a policy was formulated for collecting the records of local municipalities including Burnaby, Coquitlam, Port Coquitlam, Maple Ridge, and Mission. In 1993, the decision was made to return these materials to their respective municipalities. Series consists of records arising from the University Archives original accessions and subsequent deaccessions of various municipal records. Series includes correspondence, memoranda, notes, copies of agreements, research papers, articles, lists, and inventories.
  - Burnaby correspondence and reference material, 1970 - 1991; F-51-3-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 51-11)
    Open
  - Burnaby inventory, 1980 - 1989; F-51-3-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 51-11)
  - Burnaby maps and plans inventory, 1990 - 1999; F-51-3-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 51-11)
  - Coquitlam lists and reference material, 1979; F-51-3-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 51-11)
  - Port Coquitlam correspondence and lists, 1975 - 1997; F-51-3-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 51-11)
  - Port Coquitlam inventories, 1976 - 1981; F-51-3-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 51-11)
  - Maple Ridge correspondence, 1974 - 1990; F-51-3-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 51-11)
  - Mission correspondence, 1965 - 1994; F-51-3-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 51-11)
- Arrangement and description, 1968 - 1978; F-51-4; 4 cm of textual records
  Early records classification and description practices at the University Archives resulted in the establishment of a record group system of arrangement for university records, and a manuscript group system for records from private sources. This system is no longer in place, and the Archives is currently undertaking the redescription of its holdings. Series consists of records arising from the development of records classification schemes and descriptive practices at the University Archives. Series includes drafts and revised lists of records groups, and copies of early descriptions of records held at the University Archives.
  - Record Groups - Classification, 1968; F-51-4-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 51-12)
  - Record Groups - Preliminary, 1978; F-51-4-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 51-12)
  - Record Groups - Revised, 1978; F-51-4-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 51-12)
  - Record group descriptions [file missing], F-51-4-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 51-12)
- Reference, 1973 - 1994; F-51-5; 7 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records arising from reference activities of the University Archives. Series includes researcher log books.
  - Researcher log book, 1973 - 1981; F-51-5-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 51-12)
  - Researcher log book, 1982 - 1994; F-51-5-0-0-2 (Archival box - small 51-14)
- Projects, conferences, and workshops, 1973 - 1991; F-51-6; 13 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records arising from special projects which the Archives completed, and records from workshops and conferences in which Archives staff participated. Series includes records of an oral history conference held at SFU (including programmes and papers), records from a records management workshop, and records of an Archives survey of university committees (including lists of committees and committee members).
  - Canadian Aural/Oral History Conference at S.F.U., 1974; F-51-6-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 51-12)
  - Survey of Committees, 1973 - 1974; F-51-6-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 51-12)
  - Manual for Small Archives, 1981 - 1990; F-51-6-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 51-12)
  - Records management workshop Feb.17, 1983; F-51-6-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 51-12)
  - ACA Canadian University Archives Survey, 1985; F-51-6-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 51-12)
  - Task Force for College Archives, 1986 - 1991; F-51-6-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 51-12)
  - Handbook for Records Management and College Archives, 1987 - 1989; F-51-6-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 51-12)
  - SFU Archives Automated Photo Index Project, 1984; F-51-6-0-0-8 (Archival box - small 51-14)
- Photographs, 1981 - 1986; F-51-7; 3 cm of textual records 244 photographs: negative prints 26 photographs: contact sheets; PHYSICAL DESCRIPTION: 244 photographs (negative prints)/26 photographs (contact sheets) located in F-51-7-0-0-1, F-51-7-0-0-2, F-51-7-0-0-3
  Series consists of negatives and contact sheets of Archives faculty and staff, University functions (Convocation guest speakers) and construction. Series includes Fine and Performing Arts posters, Simon Fraser Student Society events, students and faculty.
  - Photographic negatives, 1981 - 1985; F-51-7-0-0-1 (Folder 51-15)
    Textual records; Photographic materials
  - Photographic negatives, 1985 - 1986; F-51-7-0-0-2 (Folder 51-15)
  - Photographic contact sheets, 1981 - 1986; F-51-7-0-0-3 (Folder 51-15)
- Archives establishment and organization, 1967 - 1987; F-51-8; 13 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records dealing with the establishment of the University Archives, the evolution of policies and procedures, and the history of the position of University Archivist. Includes correspondence, reports and other documents.
  - Policy and procedures, 1967 - 1972; F-51-8-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 51-13)
  - Policy and procedures, 1972 - 1977; F-51-8-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 51-13)
  - Policy and procedures, 1975 - 1980; F-51-8-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 51-13)
  - Policy and procedures, 1979 - 1984; F-51-8-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 51-13)
  - University Archivist position, 1973 - 1987; F-51-8-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 51-13)